Okay, let's pray and let's get into the
word. Heavenly Father,
I want to ask your blessing upon your
people.
Lord, send your angels to give us
understanding.
This we pray in Jesus name. Amen.
Daniel
chapter 12.
Daniel 12
beginning with verse one. And the Bible
says, "And at that time shall Michael
stand up, the great prince which
standeth for the children of thy people.
And there shall be a time of trouble
such as never was since there was a
nation even to that same time, and at
that time thy people shall be delivered,
everyone that shall be found written in
the book." Verse three, they that be
wise shall shine as the brightness of
the firmament, and they that turn many
to righteousness as the stars forever.
Verse four, but thou, oh Daniel, shut up
the words and seal the book,
even to the time of the end. Many shall
run to and fro, and knowledge shall be
increased. Verse 10, many shall be
justified and made or purified and made
white and tried, and the wicked, or but
the wicked shall do wickedly, and none
of the wicked shall understand, but the
wise shall understand. How many of you
want to be among the wise at the end of
time? Amen.
Beloved, the Bible tells us that the
wise will understand the book of Daniel.
And for many of us, the book of Daniel
is just that mystery. I I don't get it.
I can't comprehend it. I don't
understand what these uh things are
talking about. And I've been to the
seminars and I've been to our meetings,
but I still can't get it. Well, today I
hope to juice the book of Daniel so that
you will never forget it.
The Bible tells us that God's people
will understand at the end of time will
will.
You should be excited.
I've learned that in Adventism the new
excitement is silence.
So, I'm in the right place.
The Bible tells us Jesus himself says
that I am the center of the scriptures.
He says the scriptures testify of me.
And I believe that when we approach the
book of Daniel, we should approach it in
this sense. Jesus says all the
scriptures testify of him. Let me give
you one example quickly. Even in those
places where we think Jesus is not,
there he is. Ellen White actually tells
us that Christ is on every page
of the Bible. There's a story in the Old
Testament of a man by the name of David
who commits adultery and and has uh uh
Basheba's husband Uriah killed. know
that story. And the Bible tells us that
that as uh uh uh David thinks he gets
away with this, but the prophet comes to
him and says uh you have sinned.
Remember, Bath Sheba is pregnant. Yes.
And and and so David repents. Praise
God. However, however, uh the prophet
says to him, "You you will live because
you repented, but the child that you
have that your your wife that Basheba is
going to have is going to die." Unfair
story. How many of you say unfair story?
Yes. Haven't you read that story before
and said, "Wow, why would God punish the
child?"
So, listen, we don't know who this child
is. The child doesn't have a name. All
we know is that it was a male child,
meaning the child was the son of David.
I'm going to wait, man. I'm just going
to wait, man.
The son of David was brought into this
world because of someone else's sin.
And and died that someone else might
live.
Christ, beloved, is the center of the
scriptures. Amen. And the same is true
in the book of Daniel. So, let's go
through the book of Daniel very quickly.
We're just going to juice it down and
we're just setting up for what I'm
actually going to talk about. But let's
consider Daniel. Daniel uh is a man who
was brought into captivity not because
of his own sin. Yeah. Okay. Oh yeah.
Silence.
Yeah. Yeah. Daniel was was was a fellow
slave with his brothers even though we
know that it was not Daniel was not a s
Daniel did not sin. And it was not
Daniel's sins that that uh led him to
Babylon, but or led him to into
captivity, but he was actually a captive
with his brothers though there's no
recorded sin of him.
That reminds me of Jesus who came to
this world though he had no sin on him
to be brothers with us. In Daniel
chapter 1, you remember that Daniel's
first temptation
appetite.
Let me ask you, when Jesus comes on the
scene, when he begins his ministry, what
is his first temptation?
Appetite.
In Daniel chapter 2, we have this image
of a man who who the Bible says he's
destroyed by a stone being dashed
against the foot. See that those that
image in Daniel 2 is really symbolic of
the kingdoms of this world which Satan
operates.
And Satan understood that when Jesus
came to this world, he was coming to
destroy that kingdom. So, you know what
Satan does in the second temptation? He
says, um, "Hey, throw yourself down. You
will not surely dash
your foot against a stone. I'm going to
try to destroy you before you can
destroy
my kingdom."
In Daniel chapter 3, Daniel is invited
to bow down. Y'all not feeling me that
bow down and worship, but Daniel
refuses. Hm. Rings a bell to me. I don't
know about you.
In Daniel chapter 4, uh there's a dream
of of Nebuchadnezzar has this dream of
this great big tree. And the Bible says,
literally says that the tree, its
branches reached out into the heavens
and all the files of the air lodge in
that tree. Let me ask you a question.
Does that term sound f does it sound
like it's used anywhere else in the
scriptures?
Did Jesus himself describe the kingdom
of heaven like a great big tree whose
branches reach out and all the birds of
the air lodge in that tree?
You see, Nebuchadnezzar felt that his
tree, his kingdom was a kingdom that was
kingdom that was going to last forever.
But he was wrong. That was not the tree.
There was another tree coming.
There was another tree coming. And that
tree, the cross of Calvary, represents
the kingdom of heaven. That's the tree
that will stand forever. Amen.
In Daniel chapter 5, you know the story.
Cyrus
uh uh is about to take over the
Babylonian Empire. And what's
interesting about this is that Cyrus,
the way that he conquered the kingdom
is that he dried up the deep. The Bible
says he dried up the deep and basically
uh hh uh descended into the riverbed to
open the gates in order to set the
captives free. Y'all not
Oh. Oh, yeah. Yeah. That's right.
Because Jesus did the same thing. By the
way, Cyrus is a type of Jesus.
You know what happens in Daniel chapter
6, right?
Daniel is put in a lion's den. A stone
is rolled over the tomb. Y'all not
feeling me? With a seal. Huh?
Daniel's not supposed to come out of
that. But guess what? He comes out.
Wow. Wow. Who would have thought that
Daniel chapters 1-6 reflect or a or a
are a shadow of the events of Christ's
life.
We get to Daniel chapter 7 and we have
the 1260 years. We get to Daniel chapter
8 and we have the 2300 day prophecy. In
other words, beloved, if you just kind
of remember the book of Daniel, what I'm
trying to do is I'm trying to help you
to to see the book of Daniel in a little
different light to help you to
understand it. I don't have time to go
through the rest of this. Let me share
one more thing with you very quickly
before we begin to put this together.
Let's go back to Daniel chapter 1
because we just seen that Christ is is a
is a a shadow in the book of Daniel. But
now we're going to see that you are in
the book of Daniel. You
you see in Daniel chapter 1 uh we have
uh uh Shadrach, Meshach, and Abednego
and Daniel. And what is the king trying
to do?
He's trying to get them to
eat
and drink what,
right? Eat his food and drink his his
wine.
Um
what's the name of the kingdom?
So, whose wine is it?
Okay. So, in Daniel chapter 1, we have
the king of Babylon trying to get God's
people to drink the wine of Babylon.
Yeah. But they don't. And as a result of
not drinking the wine of Babylon, they
are 10 times wiser. Y'all not feeling
me, man. Y'all not feeling me.
Will there be an end time people who are
10 times wiser because they refuse to
drink the wine of Babylon? Yeah. Yeah.
Daniel chapter 2. As a result of them
refusing to drink the wine of Babylon,
the Bible says they preach a message to
Nebuchadnezzar that your kingdom Babylon
is going to fall. Y'all not feeling me?
In Daniel chapter 3, the king Bab the
king of Babylon is angry. And so in
response to this message that Babylon
will fall, what does he do? He sets up
an image and commands all to bow down.
Are you following this?
You see, when he does this, then Babylon
will have fallen.
Daniel chapter 4.
when or Babylon's sins will have reached
unto heaven. I should say Daniel chapter
4. That tree whose height reached unto
heaven. And when her sins reach unto
heaven, guess what? She will fall. Just
as in Daniel chapter 5.
A and just as in Daniel chapter 6, there
was a death decree issued for those who
refuse to keep the law of the land.
But fear not. Daniel 7, the little horn
will come to his end. Daniel 8, the
sanctuary will be cleansed. Daniel 9,
probation will close on those who reject
the Messiah. Daniel 11, the king of the
north will come to his end. And Daniel
12, Michael will stand up and the dead
shall rise.
Let's do another little practice very
quickly. Um because there's something
else you need to understand about the
book of Daniel and those are the time
prophecies and there are basically three
time prophecies in the book of Daniel.
There is Daniel, there is a 70we
prophecy, there is a 1260 and there is a
2300. Now how many of you have
difficulty understanding or remembering
these prophecies? Let me see your hands.
Be honest. All right. I know a lot more
hands wanted to go up, but
here's how I want you to remember it.
In Daniel, the 70we prophecy is really
about the coming of Jesus Christ. Very
simple. Amen. Jesus comes to Jerusalem.
Jesus comes to his temple. That's what
Malachi 3:1 says. The Lord whom you seek
shall suddenly come to his temple. This
is a reflection of the 70we prophecy. So
I want you to personalize the 70we
prophecy.
When Jesus, the seven prophecy points to
Jesus coming to his people. Amen. How
many of you have received Jesus into
your heart? You are a 70 weaker.
Did you catch that just now? Right.
Jesus on a personal level has come to
you. You've accepted him. Now you know
that if you rejected him, what would
happen?
You you get what I'm saying? The same
thing that happened to Israel in
rejecting the literal coming of Christ
is the same thing that happens to us if
we reject Christ spiritually coming in
our in our hearts.
Now what prophecy comes after the 70
weeks? The 1260. You know what the 1260
prophecy is about?
It's about persecution.
See many of us when we get baptized we
think man it's going to be great. I have
accepted the Lord and all things are
going to be very good from now on.
Little do you realize
that after the 70 comes
1260.
How many of you have experienced 1260?
Are you with me? I'm just personalizing
this for you. I'm not doing away with
the actual meaning of the prophecy. I'm
just trying to help you to kind of grasp
the book a little bit easier so that
when you go to study it, you have more
anchor points that you can study it
from. All right. So, we know that
there's a 1260, but God says, "Don't
worry because just as I was with the
woman in the wilderness during the 1260
feeding her and keeping her, so I will
be with you."
Because ultimately after the 1260, there
is the
2300.
And you know what the good news about
the 2300 day prophecy is? The sanctuary.
The sanctuary
will be cleansed.
Hold on. Where is the record of sin?
It's in the temple, isn't it? The record
of sin was in the temple.
So God cleanses the record of sin from
the temple.
The record of sin was in the temple.
So when the sanctuary is cleansed,
the record of sin, the record of sin,
which is why Ellen White tells us
there's coming a time where the
righteous are trying to remember.
Are you following me? And they cannot.
Why? because the record of sin has been
removed from the temple.
Let's put this all together.
Come with me to Daniel chapter 11.
While we're turning there,
this is what I want you to understand.
I'm going to speak to you in in
numerical language. When you accept
Christ, you become a what?
70 weaker. And and Christ ultimately
wants to lead you to become a 23
hunder. I just made that up. 2300er.
Right now, when you are 2300er, your
mission is to turn people who have not
accepted Christ into 70 weakers.
However, there are some who are already
70 weakers and love Jesus. They are just
in the wrong 1260.
All right. All right. So, our mission is
to move them from 1260 to 23. All right.
How many of you will never forget the
23, 1260 or Very good. Okay. Now, now
Daniel 11, I'm going to show you. How
many of you ever tried to read through
Daniel 11? All right. It's a very, very
complicated chapter. But here's what
we're going to do. We're going to juice
Daniel 11 down for you right now. I'm
not going to give you any answers as to
what is what. I'm just going to show you
just one simple thing. Okay. So in
Daniel 11, you'll you'll notice that it
begins uh with the Meo Persian Empire.
Daniel 11:1 also I in the first year of
Darius the me even I uh stood to confirm
and to strengthen him. The vision of
Daniel 11 begins with the Meo Persian
Empire. If you jump down with me to
verse 23,
verse 23. When you get there, just say
amen. Amen.
I'm sorry. Verse 22.
The Bible says, "And with the arms of a
flood shall they be overflown from
before him, and shall be broken. Ya,
also the prince of the covenant." Now,
who does that sound like to you? The
prince of the covenant.
Prince of the covenant is Jesus Christ.
So, I want you to watch this. In Matthew
chap in Daniel 11:es 1 to23 you have a
prophecy that begins with Meo Persia
and takes us all the way to the death,
burial and resurrection of Jesus Christ.
Is there a prophecy that reminds you of
that time period that would begin in the
Meo Persian Empire and conclude with the
coming of Christ and his death, burial,
resurrection, etc. The 70 week prophecy.
Very good. Very good. So, hey pastor, I
didn't know that the 7we prophecy in
shadow form is in Daniel 11, the first
23 verses or 22 verses. Now, in verse
23,
and uh you know there is some uh some
debate about this, but let me just share
it anyway. In verse 23, the Bible says,
"And after the league made with him, uh
he shall work the seed for these four,
he shall come up uh and shall become
strong with a small people." Now, when
you hear something in in the book of
Daniel that starts out small but grows
big,
starts out little
but grows. What do you think of? You
think of the little the little horn,
right? So, so some believe that this is
uh verse 23 is the little horn. I am one
of them. Some dispute that. But let me
just share this anyway. From verse 23
when you get to verse 40, verse 40 says,
"And at the time of the end." Now, let
me ask you a question. What do we
understand as the time of the end? What
when did that begin? 1798. So 1798
concludes the what prophecy? The 12 s.
Very good. So watch this. Then from
Daniel chapter 1 to 22, you have the 70
weeks. And then somewhere between verse
23 to 40, you evidently have the 1260,
which means that the events that unfold
from verses 40 all the way to Daniel
12:1 and 2 would encompass the 2300
day prophecy. How do you feel?
Everybody okay?
Yeah. What we just saw is is is simply
that these three time prophecies help us
to break down Daniel 11. That's all
without any detail, without any
whatever. We've just seen, wow, these
time prophecies are in Daniel 11, even
though it's not written out 70 weeks or
1260 or 2300. Why? Because Daniel 11 is
an amplification of that which comes
before it. So in Daniel 11, we have the
70, the 1260, the 2300, which leads to
Michael
standing up. Now, all of that was
preliminary stuff.
We're about to get into the meat of the
message this morning. And don't worry,
I'm not going to hold you long. Daniel
chapter 12, Michael stands up. How many
of you believe that Michael is coming
again?
You honestly believe that? Let me ask
you a question. Have you ever laughed
at the promises of God? Probably.
How many of you believe Jesus is coming
again? Some of you are laughing
and you're looking at me dead serious
like, "What in the world are you talking
about, pastor?"
Come with me. Genesis chapter 18.
Genesis chapter 18. And I'm going to
show you something that uh you'll be
familiar with. In Genesis chapter 18,
beloved, we have to know what we believe
and why we believe it. Amen. In Genesis
chapter 18, you find there the story of
Abraham
and Sarah. And you'll remember that God
visits Abraham and he visits him with
two other uh uh angels. And the Bible
tells us that they they speak to Abraham
and then they tell Abraham uh in Genesis
18, "Hey Abraham, your wife Sarah is
going to bear a child."
And you know what Sarah does?
She laughs.
Now, she laughed in her heart. She
didn't laugh out loud. Y'all not feeling
me?
She laughed in her heart. A and and and
so God hears it because God hears all
the and God said, "Why did she laugh?"
And then Sarah hears, she's like, "Oh, I
didn't laugh." And he said, "No, but you
did laugh. You will have a son." Who was
that son? Isaac. You will have a son.
Now, you got to understand why Sarah
laughed because she had been uh it had
been almost 25 years since the promise
first came to her. You're going to have
a son.
And you can imagine on on on on the day
she hears that, she's thinking, "Yeah,
man. My my stomach is about to start
forming." Woo! I'm about to have a baby.
Eight months pass, no baby. But she's
like, "Hey, I'm not worried. God is
always on time." Amen.
Two years pass, not a problem. He is
going to keep his word. Amen. 10 years,
15 years, 20 years.
Listen, not only did Sarah laugh, but in
the chapter before, God says to Abraham,
"Abraham, you're going to have a son."
And Abraham
didn't even have the decency to laugh
inside.
He laughed outside.
And then he says these words, listen
carefully. Let Ishmael live forever.
Listen carefully, guys. Abraham thought
the promise was to be fulfilled through
Ishmael.
Please mark that down in your mind. Mark
it down. Come. So, I want to show you
the context of this laughter. We're in
Genesis chapter 19 or 18. This is where
Sarah laughs in Genesis 18. Come back
with me to Genesis chapter 1. In Genesis
chapter 1, uh, uh, we have the
introduction of, you know, the creation
and then you have the fall of man. And
then by the time we get to Genesis
chapter 6, sin has become so bad that
God is going to destroy the world. Yes.
And so, how does he what does he do? He
calls a man by the name of Noah. And he
says to Noah, "Build an ark made of
wood. And you, this ark is going to be
the salvation of those who choose it."
So, so how long was Noah to preach? 120
years. The very first time prophecy in
the Bible.
Yeah, I feel that
was about the coming
was about a man who would be the
salvation of the world by being lifted
up on a piece of wood. Y'all not feeling
me? above the earth.
The name Noah means rest. Come unto me
all you that labor and are heavy laden
and I will give you rest. Think about
this. Is there another prophecy in the
Bible that speaks of a probation for
mankind in which a man would come be
lifted up on wood above the earth and
those who accept him would be saved or
carry on and those who reject him would
be cut off.
You know that's Genesis chapter 6,
chapter 7, chapter 8 all cover the same
thing. When we get to Genesis chapter
11, we now have this. It is a story of a
flood.
Not not the flood. Story of the tower of
Babel. The tower of what everyone? Okay.
Tell me about the tower of Babel.
Oh, the the tower of Babel ascended
where? To heaven. Does that remind you
of any power?
Are are you with me? Yeah. Yeah. Check
this out, guys. So So there's another
power in the B in the Bible called
Babylon. Babylon is said to rule for how
long? The little horn is set to rule for
how long? 1260
years. During this time, they're they
are attempting to usurp the position of
God.
Now, now, now you got to follow this,
guys. At the end of Daniel 11, listen
carefully. You have Abraham being called
I'm sorry, Genesis
11. You have Abraham being called out.
Just give me a moment to be excited by
myself. Okay.
You have Abraham being called out of
the Caldes. You know where that is?
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait. I
got to come down here and do this.
God says to Abraham, I'm calling you out
of Babylon and you are going to produce
a great multitude.
No, no, no.
Abraham,
I'm calling you out of Babylon
and you are going to produce a great
multitude.
Did God call an end time people out of
Abraham to produce a great multitude?
Okay.
So Abraham,
what is he waiting for? What was the
promise to Abraham?
So Abraham was promised
uh a son. Abraham the promised son is
coming.
Abraham the promised son is coming.
The one that was promised is coming.
7th Day Adventist 1844. I've called you
out of Babylon. Oh yeah. And Jesus is
coming again. Amen.
1844. Jesus doesn't come. Not a problem.
1846.
He's coming. Amen.
1848.
Jesus coming again.
Amen.
1890.
1920.
Amen.
1990.
No, no, no, no. 1999. Amen. Amen. Amen.
2001. Amen.
2018.
No, no, no, no, no, no. Don't say amen.
You want to know why? Because many of
you are laughing.
You're la you're laughing at me with
working with these headphones. You're
laughing
inside.
Why? Because I've heard that all my
life.
Yeah, my parents thought that and their
parents thought that and their parents'
parents I'm a fifth generation
Adventist, a sixth generation Adventist.
So, you know, you can't laugh out loud
because that would be disrespectful. So,
you just laugh inside,
but you say amen.
Beloved, listen to me. Jesus is coming
again. Amen. G look look what what are
the odds that in Genesis from Genesis
chapter 1 all the way to Genesis chapter
18 it's as though God foreshadowed our
very movement.
But wait in case some of you are still
like well I don't know. Hold on.
After God tells Abraham you will have a
son. What does he do next?
Wait.
He says, "All right, Abraham.
Now,
I'm going to investigate."
I'm going down to Sodom and Gomorrah to
investigate.
Yeah.
Hold on.
How many of them went to Sodom
altogether?
How many messengers?
Three.
Yeah.
God says to Abraham, "I'm going to Sodom
and Gomorrah because I'm going to
investigate." And you know what Abraham
does? Abraham doesn't say, "Yes, get
those wicked people. Woohoo." No. He
goes, "Wait a minute.
Wait a minute, Lord. Lord, hold on." and
he begins to intercede for the lost.
Beloved, listen to me. If you want to
know what we ought to be doing in this
time of the three angels messages,
in this time of the investigative
judgment, what we ought to be doing is
interceding for those who are lost while
we wait for the coming Isaac. Y'all not
feeling me?
You see beloved, listen to me. God has
given us as a church the ministry of
reconciliation.
All right? But how can we reconcile
others to God if we can't even reconcile
among ourselves?
Listen, does God follow his own advice?
So if God had an issue with us, what
would he do?
Let us reason together. He would come
himself. Did Jesus come here himself?
Hey guys, I have a problem with you.
You've sinned. And our response was,
"Well, we don't like you. We're going to
crucify you." So, we crucify him. 70we
prophecy.
Well, you know how it goes, right? If
you come and they don't listen to you,
what do you do?
You send or bring two witnesses.
[Music]
Did God send two witnesses in Revelation
11? A prophecy that we know at the 1260.
Did God send two witnesses?
And what did they do with the two
witnesses?
They rejected them.
So, you know what God's last
hope for the world is? He raised up
a church.
And he said, "Listen, I need you to go
to my people
and tell them,
preach the everlasting gospel to them."
Beloved, how can we do that if we're not
even
able to reconcile among ourselves?
Listen,
the Bible says that Michael's going to
stand up.
You got to follow this.
Do you know that the only time Michael
is used in the scripture, you know,
Michael is only used four times in the
scripture. Did you know that? Twice in
the book of Daniel, Daniel chapter 10
and Daniel chapter 12. Right before
Daniel chapter 11 and right after Daniel
chapter 11. The other two times, check
this out guys.
The other two times the name Daniel is
used, Michael, I'm sorry, is used is in
da in Revelation 12:7
where Michael fights against the dragon
and in Jude where Michael approaches
Satan for the body of Moses.
Check this out.
In Daniel 12:1, Michael stands up and
he's about to come. In Jude, Michael
is taking the body of Moses to heaven.
Michael is the name that is used
when Jesus goes to battle personally
against Satan.
So, why do you think Michael is used in
Daniel 12?
Why does Michael stand up in Daniel
chapter 12?
May I share with you why? Come back with
me to Daniel 12.
In Daniel 12,
in fact, let's not go to Daniel 12. I'm
going to show you something else. Come
with me to Isaiah,
the book of Isaiah.
Isaiah chapter 40 65.
Isaiah the 65th chapter.
And while you're turning there, Isaiah
65:15. I want you to go there and I want
you to hold your place there.
The parable of the 10 virgins. How many
of you want to be wise,
right? What does the Bible say? The wise
will do what? Will understand. Listen,
guys. When do the 10 virgins wake up?
When do they wake up? They wake up at at
midnight. So, what does midnight
represent?
It is the darkest hour of earth's
history. It is the hour that leads
Michael to do what? Stand up. Now
remember, Michael is the name that is
used when when Jesus is about to
confront
Satan personally.
Michael only appears when it's to
confront Satan personally.
So if Michael stands up, what does that
indicate is going on on earth?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Let me ask you something.
Beautiful situation is Mount Zion, the
city of the great king on the sides of
the north. Who is the true king of the
north?
Who's the true king of the north? Jesus.
The true king of the north, Jesus,
stands up when a counterfeit
attempts to claim that title.
when I was uh before I became an
Adventist,
I used to believe in the secret rapture.
And um I wasn't a Christian, but I knew
about the rapture. I didn't believe in
it. I knew about it. I said to myself, I
don't really believe in God, but if I
see people disappearing, then I'll know
it's time to get ready
and I'll have seven years.
Guess what? Adventists have their own
version.
See, Adventists think
that what we're watching for is a Sunday
law.
I'mma party in the clubs, do my thing,
and if I see Congress starting to talk
about a Sunday law, then I'll know.
And you know how long Congress takes to
do anything. So you're like, "Yeah,
okay. They still No, no, no. That's not
what happens in the parable, beloved.
It's something that catches everyone.
Even the wise are caught off guard."
You see, beloved, Satan does not
announce when he comes.
And when he comes, Ellen White says it
will be the greatest delusion that
mankind has ever seen. And listen to me.
Hold on, guys.
Remember, Abraham thought that the
promise was to be fulfilled in Ishmael.
[Music]
Ishmael came before
Isaac.
May I dare say that there will be
seventh day Adventists
who will accept the counterfeit
instead of the genuine.
You say, "Pastor, that's not that's not
possible." Cuz we know his feet don't
touch the ground.
We got it. No, no, no, no, no. Beloved,
listen to me. By the way, Loly tells us
that when Satan appears, it will be more
majestic than anything human eyes have
ever seen.
The Bible says in in Isaiah 65:14 that
when Jesus comes, he comes with a fire
and with chariots and a whirlwind.
Listen carefully, guys. He comes When
Jesus comes, it's with fire and chariots
and a whirlwind.
So, when Satan comes, guess what? what
he's going to try to do. He's going to
try to imitate that.
You think, "Oh, I got it." You remember
John the Revelator? John the Revelator
in Revelation 19 is talking to an angel.
And this angel is so glorious to John
that John the Revelator, the same guy
who knows that you don't bow down before
angels, is so overtaken by the glory
that he his knees begin to buckle.
John the Any Any Any Any Any Any Any Any
Any Any Any Johns in here? Any John the
Revelators in here?" John the Revelator,
the guy that knew Jesus, his knees begin
to buckle
and you think, "Oh, his feet don't touch
the ground."
You think he got it, two chapters later,
he does the same thing.
Beloved, listen to me. If you don't know
what you believe and why you believe it,
how do you think you're going to do when
when when Jesus
comes again?
Not only does he come by himself,
because you got to you got to hear this,
love. In the book of Revelation, we're
told that three unclean spirits like
frogs
go out to deceive the whole world.
Anyone want to know why the Bible uses
these this term frogs? Let me tell you
why. Where do frogs where do the where
else do we read about frogs in the
Bible?
in the Exodus. And you remember that the
magicians were able to counterfeit the
miracle of the serpent and then the
water and then the frogs. And the frogs
were the last miracle that they could
counterfeit.
It was the last miracle that they could
Beloved, when Satan comes again, we are
told that it is the crowning act. It is
the last miracle. And it is that
miracle. Listen carefully. How many of
you ever wonder how in the world is the
whole world going to come together to
keep Sunday?
How are atheists and radical Islamists
and Buddhists and Hindus and agnostics,
you know what it would take to bring the
whole world together?
It would take a miracle.
Yeah.
Because listen to me, for an atheist,
seeing
is believing.
And when Satan comes,
not only when Satan comes, when Satan
comes, guess what else we're told? It
will be made to appear that the dead are
among us.
So, let me ask you, how are you going to
do if you are struggling with what you
believe now? If you're laughing in your
heart now, if you're not sure now, how
are you going to do when Satan himself
appears as Jesus? And not only that, but
we're told that the dead will be like,
"Oh, yeah, you were wrong. Your pastors
were wrong." How you going to do when
your Adventist relatives
appear to you,
we got it all wrong.
You see, beloved, listen to me. and
Satan comes again. The Bible tells us
that that or in in great controversy
tells us that the world will be saying
this is the long expected millennium.
Check this out guys. The millennium,
you know what happens in the millennium?
Jesus gives judgment unto his saints.
No, not amen for this one.
Because Jesus
is going to give judgment
unto his saints.
Who are the saints?
When Jesus comes again as Satan,
he's going to give judgment to the
saints.
And the wicked will be those who do not
go along.
So guess who becomes the wicked?
And if you don't know who you are,
if you don't know your identity in
Christ, if you don't know why you
believe what you believe, let me tell
you, the overwhelming delusion, as Ellen
White calls it, will sweep
you up.
Satan will create a whole role reversal.
You want to know why the Bible says
it'll be a time of trouble such as never
was.
That's why
beloved, if you don't know what you
believe and why you believe it,
if you don't have the oil in your vessel
so that you can see you have light,
how will you do
when this delusion takes the whole
world?
Listen, I'm getting ready to close.
When I was younger,
I moved from Jamaica to New York
and I moved by an airport.
My my my family actually lived by an
airport. I remember the first time that
I went there and I was outside and I
heard this plane coming over the and I
thought the house was going to like
break apart. I'm 6 years old and I'm
looking around and no one's moving, no
one's responding, nothing. And I'm like,
did they not just hear that incredibly
loud noise?
But you know what happened? They had
gotten used to that noise.
It had become
white noise.
It had become white noise.
And beloved, for many of us,
these things we've been hearing
year after year has become
white noise.
So that we no longer take it seriously.
We laugh. We don't study anymore. We're
not really like, you know, whatever.
Let's just hear something that's going
to like, you know, ease us or whatever.
Listen to me.
If we are not awake now, listen. Listen
guys, you don't prepare for a marathon
on the day of a marathon.
And that's what many of us are doing.
We're thinking, "Oh, we're going to have
time, whatever." When this thing
happens, it will hit as an overwhelming
surprise. It will catch everyone off
guard. And beloved, if you're not
preparing now,
you do not prepare for a marathon on the
day of the marathon. That's what we
would call stupidity.
And this is exactly what the 10 virgins,
the five foolish virgins do.
They wait. They chill. They hang out.
And then when it's too late, they're
like, "Give us of the oil." But you know
what? They end up getting foreign oil.
Strange oil. It's not the Holy Spirit.
Because they end up being deceived.
Beloved,
Jesus is coming again. Do you believe
it?
I don't know if that sound convincing or
not. Jesus is coming again. Do you
believe it?
God is calling a people to be ready. God
is calling a people to be prepared. God
is calling a people to remember that
Michael will come. And those who
understand, those that turn many to
righteousness, will shine as the stars
forever. If you're ready to shine, if
you're ready to say, "Lord, Lord, no
more. I don't want to be one of those
people who just I don't really know and
understand. I want to understand. Take
me deeper in your word. Help me to have
a greater understanding." If that's your
desire, I want to ask you to just stand
where you are, Lord. Help me. Help me to
be ready when you come again.
Heavenly Father,
I want to thank you Lord
that you are coming again.
I want to thank you
that the soon return
will redeem your people.
That we will be in heaven with you. But
Father, we know that a time of trouble
is coming.
that in that time of trouble,
it will be such a time as no other time
in this world's history.
Lord, help us not to be among those that
are deceived, that are fooled, that are
caught up
by this counterfeit Christ.
Lord, please make our footing on solid
ground.
Fill us, Lord. Fill us with your mercy,
with your grace, with your presence.
Cleanse our temples.
And Lord, we thank you
for coming to save us.
This is our prayer. We pray it in the
precious name of Jesus. Amen. Amen. You
may be seated.